<Document>

# Farming

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CEGuidebookFarmingDummy"/>
</Box>

You have the ability to grow various plants and crops in CrystallEdge!

# Seeds

To start growing plants, you will need seeds.
Seeds are typically obtained by [color=yellow]cutting fruits[/color] using a sharp tool.

[color=yellow]Not all plants have seeds[/color]! For example, to grow potatoes, you need to plant the tubers themselves.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CEFoodPepper"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CEWeaponDaggerHatchet"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CEFoodPepperSlice"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CESeedPepper"/>
</Box>

# Soil

Different plants may require different types of soil for planting.
Also, some types of soil may be more or less effective, affecting the growth rate of the plant.

You can find out how effective the soil type being used is by examining the growing plant.

- Most domesticated crops grow best on [color=yellow]soil beds[/color]. You can create a bed by using dirt blocks on top of soil tiles.
- Mushrooms grow best on [color=yellow]Mycelium[/color]. Mycelium seeds can be purchased from the store and placed on the ground.
- Wild plants grow effectively right on [color=yellow]grass tiles[/color].
- You can also use a shovel to remove grass, mycelium, and dig up soil.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CEDirtBlock10"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CEFloorTileGrass"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CEFloorTileMycelium"/>
</Box>
<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CEWeaponShovelIron"/>
</Box>

# Watering

To make a plant grow faster, it must be [color=yellow]watered[/color]. In the future, different plants may require different reagents, but for now it's only water...
The only water source in the game right now is unfinished - these are unattractive water tiles that exist on every map.

If you don't water the plant, it won't die, but it will grow significantly slower.

Different plants require watering at different frequencies - some need to be watered twice a day, while others only need it once every 2 days.

Examine the plant to see if it has drunk all the water or not.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CEBucket"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CEWaterFloorEntity"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CEBucket"/>
</Box>

# Lighting

Most plants require [color=yellow]natural light[/color] to grow.
Mushrooms are an exception - they prefer darkness.

</Document>
