<Document>

# Punishment System
## Minor and Minor-Medium Offenses:

1.	Light Monetary/Material fines - Of up to 5 silver or the amount stolen. While 5 silver is the maximum it is not recommended to charge that much for minor offenses.

2.	Community service - Giving back to the community. For example: cleaning, building a house, chef work.

3.	Ban on conducting activity - A ban on conducting your current job.

4.	An apology to the injured party - A sincere heartfelt apology to the injured party.

## Medium and Medium-Serious Offenses:

1.  Heavy Monetary/Material fines - Of up to 5 gold or the amount stolen. While 5 gold is the maximum it is not recommended to charge that much for medium offenses.

2.	Hard labor - Labor in the guard camp or in the underground with a pickaxe, a guard should watch over if the criminal is outside a guard area.

3.	Retribution through duel - A duel set up in a set area where either the injured party or a guard fights till one drops. The injured party selects the weapon.

## Serious Crimes:

1.	Sent to the arena - If the arena is available criminals can be sent here to prove themselves against multiple opponents.

2.	Public execution - Reserved for criminals who either are far too dangerous to ever be let out or those who failed in the arena.

# Сrime Modifiers
## Mitigating modifiers:

1.	Self-defense – If the crime was committed to protect one's own life, property, or other people from threat, the punishment may be mitigated or completely canceled.

2.	Necessity – If the action was committed for survival (e.g., stealing food when starving), the punishment is mitigated.

3.	Inexperience (newcomer) – If the criminal has not previously committed offenses or does not understand the rules (e.g., new player), the punishment may be replaced with training or a warning.

4.	Repentance – If the criminal sincerely repents and is willing to cooperate, the punishment may be mitigated or replaced with compensation to the injured party.

Effect : The punishment is mitigated by one step (for example, the average violation is considered as easy-average).

## Aggravating modifiers:
1.	Recidivism – Repeated commission of a similar or more serious crime. Toughens punishment.

2.	Cultural aspect – If the crime violates religious canons, traditions, or laws of a specific race/faction, this is taken into account (e.g., desecration of a shrine).

3.	Intention to continue violations – If the criminal, by words or actions, confirms that after release they will continue to commit violations (Works only upon re-arrest).

4.  Violence in non-violent crimes - If the criminal does a crime that is non-violent with violence involved such as theft crimes.

Effect : Increases the punishment in the current category.

## Extremely aggravating modifiers:

1.	Victims – If the crime led to serious injuries, death, or destruction of important objects, the punishment is toughened.

2.	Organizer – The one who planned and directed the crime. The punishment will be the strictest (Works only for group violations).

3.	Wartime – If the crime was committed during a crisis or war, the punishment is toughened (e.g., for sabotage).

Effect: Transfer of the crime to the following category.

</Document>
